Confess your sins.
The Nun II is a horror film directed by Michael Chaves.
In 1956 France, a priest is violently murdered, and
Sister Irene begins to investigate.
She once again comes face-to-face with a powerful evil.
Sister Irene, played by Taissa Farmiga.
Maurice Theriault, played by Jonas Bloquet.
Sister Debra, played by Storm Reid.
Kate, played by Anna Popplewell.
The Demon Nun / Valak, played by Bonnie Aarons.
Sophie, played by Katelyn Rose Downey.
The Nun II is a 2023 American gothic supernatural horror film directed by Michael Chaves, with a
screenplay written by Ian Goldberg, Richard Naing, and Akela Cooper from a story by Cooper.
Serving as a sequel to The Nun (2018) and the eighth installment in The Conjuring Universe franchise, the film stars Taissa Farmiga,
Jonas Bloquet, and Bonnie Aarons, returning from the first film, with Storm Reid and Anna Popplewell joining the cast.
Peter Safran and James Wan return as producers.
In 2017, Wan discussed the possibility of a Nun sequel and by 2019,
Safran revealed that the film was in early development.
Cooper was initially hired as the sole writer, before Goldberg and
Naing contributed as screenwriters to the final script.
Chaves, who had previously helmed The Conjuring: The Devil Made Me Do It (2021)
and The Curse of La Llorona (2019), was announced as director.
Principal photography began in October 2022 in France.
The Nun II was released in the United States by Warner Bros.
Pictures on September 8, 2023.
The film was a commercial success, grossing $269 million
worldwide, and received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of france, nun, halloween, bullying, sequel.
The tone is dark.